SHIVAM SINGH

Software Engineer

□ 9729122369
□ ss083200@gmail.com
□ github.com/ss083200

Summary: Highly motivated and self-driven **software engineer** with more than **1 years** of professional experience. Possesing a strong foundation in **C++**, **Python**, **Erlang**, **SQL**, web development. With a solid understanding of software engineering principles and best practices I have successfully contributed to the design, development, and deployment of various software projects.

SKILLS

• **Programming Languages**: C++, Python, Erlang

 Web-dev: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Node.JS

Databases: MySQL

 Agile Development: JIRA, GIT Confluence, Slack

• Others: Postman, Pytest, Testdriven development

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Data Structures and algorithms
- Object Oriented Programming
- DBMS
- Web development

EDUCATION

BTech

NIT Kurukshetra

Production and Industrial Engineering 2018-2022 CGPA: 8.59

Senior Secondary(CBSE)/12th grade

Apex Public School

2016-2017 Percentage: 85%

Secondary(CBSE)/10th grade

Radiant Central Academy

2014-2015

CGPA: 10

CERTIFICATIONS

- Introduction to C++ (Coding Ninjas)
- Data Structures in C++ (Coding Ninjas)
- SAFe® 5 Practitioner by Scaled Agile, Inc.

LANGUAGES

Hindi, English

HOBBIES

Volleyball, Cricket, Chess

WORK EXPERIENCE

GreyOrange (10 months)

July, 2022 - Present

Software Engineers

Worked in the core team of GreyOrange that handles the movement of robots in the warehouse. The complete microservice-based operating system handles charging, safety, task assignment, and navigation of robots for pick-up and drop operations in the warehouse.

- Single-handedly handled tasks related to power and safety management.
- Automated the process of creating dev-test environments by synchronously pulling the database from the live site. Also, automated the cleanup process, resulting in increased efficiency.
- Designed and developed a multitype bot handling system.
- Handled automation testing with development.

Technologies Used: Erlang, Mnesia, Python, Pytest

Siemens (5 months)

Jan 2021 - May 2021

Research Intern

Project: Weight Reduction of Wagons in Indian Railway

- Software used: Simcenter 3D
- Achieved a 3% weight reduction using material substitution in Simcenter 3D.
- Substituted steel with aluminum alloys(Al-2014).

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Simon Game

- Developed using HTML, CSS, and Javascript.
- In this color memory game, players must click on each color in the sequence they were presented, including the most recent color, which is randomly generated each turn.

E-Commerce System

- Developed a feature-rich E-Commerce System in C++, leveraging objectoriented programming and efficient data structures.
- Implemented user management, authentication, cart management, market management, and order placement functionalities.
- Ensured scalability and smooth user experience through optimized code and algorithmic thinking.

ToDo List

- Developed using HTML, CSS, Javascript, **Node.js**, Express.js, MongoDb.
- The website tells the current date to the user and the tasks to be performed.
- It has a database and the user can add or delete tasks accordingly.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Highest Rating of Specialist on Codeforces (handle @__Ryuk__)
- Contest Rankings: Global rank 618 in Codeforces #707 (div2).